(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-28T05:02:16.625066",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
本日はアキロゼ4th生誕祭にご来場いただき誠にありがとうございます。
Thank you very much for attending Aki Rosenthal's 4th birthday live today.
公園のスクリーン、ジフ塔の一部部分を切り抜く動画は大歓迎です！
Videos cutting out parts of the park screen and Ziff Tower are very welcome!
ハッシュタグは #アキロゼ生誕祭2022 をつけてたくさん投稿してくださいね！
Please post plenty using the hashtag #AkiRoseBirthday2022!
歌をまるっと投稿するのはご遠慮ください。
Please refrain from posting full songs.
4回目の生誕祭は今までとは一味違うテイストでお届けいたします。
This 4th birthday live will deliver a different flavor from before.
ですが公演前にとりあえずチャンネル登録お願いいたします！おずみでない方は今ならなんと無料でチャンネル登録ができます！というのは冗談ではありますが、はい。
But please subscribe beforehand! You can subscribe for free right now—just kidding!
まだの方行きますよ。せーの！はい！よくできました！
For those who haven't, here we go. Ready, go! Yes! Well done!
本日は愉快なホロライブの仲間たちと繰り広げる不思議な世界をお楽しみください。
Please enjoy this mysterious world unfolded with our cheerful Hololive friends today.
それではアキロゼ4thバースデーライブ「ワンダーシャワーミュージカル」開演いたします！
Now, Aki Rosenthal's 4th Birthday Live "Wondershower Musical" will now begin!
最後まで楽しんでってね！
Enjoy it all the way to the end!
お話をしよう
Let's tell a story,
昔話よりも
a tale even more wonderful
もっともっと素敵な
than any old story...
おとぎ話にふと目を開けると
When you open your eyes to a fairy tale,
真っ白なうさぎ
a pure white rabbit
大慌てで駆けつけて
comes rushing in a panic,
後を追うの
and I follow after it.
チクタク チクタク 急いで行かなきゃ間に合わない！
Tick-tock, tick-tock, hurry or we won't make it in time!
ああ チクタク チクタク ギクシャクするのはもう嫌だ
Ah, tick-tock, tick-tock, I'm sick of being out of sync.
そら チクタク チクタク 時間はどんどん減っていく
Look, tick-tock, tick-tock, time is steadily running out.
もう兎にも角にも私には時間がない
Anyway, I have no time left at all!
ねえ そんなに慌てて一体全体どうしたの？
Hey, why are you in such a frantic rush?
お話をしよう
Let's tell a story,
昔話よりもっともっと素敵な童話
a fairytale far more wonderful than old tales.
ふっと目を開けると真っ白なうさぎ
When I suddenly open my eyes, a pure white rabbit
大慌てで駆けっていく 後を追うのは
is rushing away in a panic, and I chase after it.
チクタク チクタク
Tick-tock, tick-tock,
急いで行かないと間に合わない！
I have to hurry or I won't make it!
ああ チクタク チクタク
Ah, tick-tock, tick-tock,
ギクシャクするのはもう嫌だ
I'm already sick of being awkward.
さら チクタク チクタク
Now then, tick-tock, tick-tock,
時間はどんどん減っていく
time is steadily ticking away.
もう兎に角 ぼくには 時間がない
Anyway, I have no time left.
ねえ そんなに慌てて 一一体全体どうしたの？
Hey, why are you in such a rush, what's going on?
どこかの誰かさんといつかどこかで待ち合わせ？
Meeting up with someone somewhere sometime?
そう！彼女はチクタク とっても時間にシビアだよ
That's right! She is tick-tock, very strict about time!
「そんなに？」
“Really?”
「そうさ！」
“That's right!”
だって彼女は女王様
Because she is the Queen.
カッカクシカジカ チクタク
So you see, tick-tock,
どうにも時間がないから
since there's no time anyway,
話があるならまたの機会にしておくれない
if you have something to say, leave it for another time.
それならひとつだけ教えて
If so, teach me just one thing:
何故そんなときでも 陽気に歌を歌うの？
Why do you cheerfully sing even at a time like this?
それはミュージックランド ワンダーランド！
That is Musicland, Wonderland!
ここがミュージックランドだからさ！
Because this is Musicland!
ああ なんて不思議な世界なのだろう
Ah, what a wondrous world this is,
この先は何が待っているのかしら
wondering what awaits us ahead.
お嬢さん？
“Young lady?”
えっ？
“Huh?”
お嬢さん？
“Young lady?”
私？
“Me?”
「そう お嬢さん」
“Yes, young lady.”
「なあに？」
“What is it?”
「君は誰？」
“Who are you?”
「私の名前は……」
“My name is...”
「君は名前なの？」
“Is that your name?”
そう言う あなたは誰なの？
Then who are you?
who am i ？ 問いかけてみよう
Who am I? Let me ask myself,
なぜ？
why?
who am i ？ 分からないんだ
Who am I? I don't know.
who are you ？ ねえ 教えてよ
Who are you? Hey, tell me.
who am i ？ 曖昧さ
Who am I? So ambiguous.
ただ分かっているのは
The only thing I know for sure is
歌ってる僕は最高にハッピーってこと
that singing makes me the happiest person ever.
you love music うたを歌えば 少しずつ見えてくる
You love music. Singing songs makes things clearer little by little.
僕が生き てる意味は きっと ここ に ある
The meaning of my life is surely right here.
「だって そう 僕は」
“Because I am—”
「そうね きっと私も」
“That's right, surely I am too—”
最高 の singer なの さ ！
The ultimate singer!
この風変わりなリズムはどこから聞こえてくるのかしら？
Where could this eccentric rhythm be coming from?
そりゃ私だよ 私んことだろ？
Well, that's me! Talking about me, right?
さあ腰掛けたら始まるぞ
Now, take a seat and it begins.
お茶はいいかが？ お茶はいいかが？
Would you like some tea? How about some tea?
楽しく飲めば世界も踊る
Drink joyfully and the world dances too.
お茶はいいかが？ さあお茶をどうぞ
Would you like some tea? Now, have some tea.
ああ なんて変なフレーバー
Ah, what a strange flavor.
普段の味に慣れちまったら
Once you get used to ordinary tastes,
全てが退屈になちまうものさ
everything becomes so boring.
ありきたりのものじゃつまらない
Ordinary things are just no fun.
それを 知ったヤツ はみんなイカレちまう のさ
Those who realize that all go mad.
（お茶はいいかが？）
(Would you like some tea?)
ほら お茶はいいかが？
Come on, how about some tea?
奇をてらいたけりゃ イカレちまえ
If you want to stand out, go mad!
お茶はいいかが？ さあお茶をどうぞ
Would you like some tea? Now, have some tea.
イカレりゃ 楽しいティータイム！
Go mad and enjoy a fun tea time!
この風変わりなリズムはどこから
Where could this eccentric rhythm
やってくるのかしら？
be coming from?
そりゃ私だよ 私のことだよ
Well, that's me! It's about me.
腰掛けたら始めるぞ
Take a seat and let's begin.
お茶はいいかが？ お茶はいいかが？
Would you like some tea? How about some tea?
楽しく飲めば世界も踊る
Drink joyfully and the world dances too.
お茶はいいかが？ さあお茶をどうぞ
Would you like some tea? Now, have some tea.
なんて変なフレーバー
What a strange flavor.
普段の味に慣れちまったら
Once you get used to ordinary tastes,
全てが退屈になちまうものさ
everything becomes so boring.
ありきたりのものじゃつまらない
Ordinary things are just no fun.
それを知ったヤツはみんなイカレちまうのさ
Those who realize that all go mad.
（お茶はいいかが？） ほらお茶はいいかが？
(Would you like some tea?) Come on, how about some tea?
奇をてらいたけりゃイカレちまえ お茶はいいかが？
If you want to stand out, go mad! How about some tea?
さあお茶をどうぞ お茶はいいかが？
Now, have some tea. Would you like some tea?
気を遣いだけじゃイカレちまえ
Just being polite won't let you go mad!
お茶はいいかが？ さあお茶をどうぞ そう イカれりゃ楽しいティータイム
Would you like some tea? Now, have some tea. Go mad and enjoy a fun tea time!
ロンリー ロンリー
Lonely, lonely,
寄り添う劣等に頬杖ついているようじゃ
resting your cheek against your clinging inferiority,
変わらない わかってるんだよ メイディー
nothing changes, I know that, maidie.
ありふれたモブなんだって認めていないなら
If you refuse to admit you're just a common mob,
いっそ腐るまで叫んで
just scream until you rot away.
異端傾けば？赤裸々に
Lean toward heresy? Bare it all.
本音ばかりじゃ生きられない
You can't survive on true feelings alone.
ロンリー ロンリー
Lonely, lonely
寄り添えない凡夫さに 頬杖突いているようじゃ
Resting my cheek on my unapproachable mediocrity,
変わらない わかってんだよ
I know it never changes.
メイビー
Maybe...
ありふれたモブなんだって 認めてないなら
If you haven't accepted you're a cliché mob,
いっそ腐るまで叫んで 異端傾けば?
why not scream until you rot and lean toward heresy?
赤裸々に 本音ばかりじゃ生きられない
You can't survive on bare honesty alone.
路傍に寝転ぶ人生が きっとお似合いだな
A life fallen by the roadside suits you best.
大人になれば溶け込んで 金と愛情で踊るのさ
Grown-ups blend in, dancing to money and love.
1 2 3で弾き飛んだ
Blown away in 1, 2, 3,
固定観念バットで打って
smashed with a stereotype bat!
どうだい?どうだい? 楽ならまあいっか
How is it? If it's easy, I guess it's fine.
レディメイドの琴線に 歪みかけてノイズ混ざり
On ready-made heartstrings, noise mixes with distortion—
後悔?後悔? やめて黙っていろ
Regrets? Regrets? Stop and keep quiet!
舌に乗せた 苦い感情ばかりが発火して
Only bitter feelings on the tongue ignite!
ダーティー ダーティー
Dirty, dirty,
言葉飲み込めばほら いい子になるわなんて
if you swallow your words, you'll be a good girl—
顔色窺ってんだよ ベイビー
reading everyone's expressions, baby!
歪み出すラブなんだって オーダーメイドのブランド
Love that starts to warp is a custom-made brand.
身につけて威張って 舌を鳴らせば下種張り と不適合者は魔女狩りさ
Wearing it proudly, and misfits are hunted as witches!
舌に乗せた 苦い感情ばかりが発火して
Only bitter feelings on the tongue ignite!
だってんだって 言葉飲み込めばほら
Because if you swallow your words, see,
イコールになるわなんて 顔色窺ってんだよ
thinking it equals being good—you're just reading expressions!
ダーティー ダーティー
Dirty, dirty,
歪み出すラブなんだって
love that starts to warp,
オーダーメイドのブランド 身につけて威張って
wearing a custom brand, showing off proudly,
舌を鳴らせば下種張り
clicking your tongue like a boor,
躓きを鳴らせばゲスパリと 不適合者は魔女狩りさ
and misfits are witch-hunted!
暖か暖かにヒール穿いて きっと楽なんだな
Wearing heels warmly, it must be easy.
社会の表はどこですか?
Where is the outside of society?
金も愛情もくそくらえ
Money and love can go to hell!
ワンツー３で砕け飛んだ
Shattered away in 1, 2, 3,
規定外で潜り乗ってんだ脳内
diving beyond regulations in my brain,
脳内 罵って笑っていろ
in my brain—mock and laugh!
レディメイドの金線に 傷口掛けてノイズ弾き飛んだ
Touching the gold wire of ready-mades, noise bursts away—
問題?問題? 遠く歌っていろ
Problem? Problem? Sing far away,
揺るがせ込んだ
shaking it deep inside!
黒い感情ばかりが発火して
Only black emotions ignite,
痛い痛い 楽ならまあいっか
it hurts, but if it's easy, I guess it's fine.
レディメイドの金銭に 歪みかけてノイズ弾き飛んだ
Warping on ready-made money, noise burst away—
後悔?後悔? やめて黙っていろ
Regrets? Regrets? Stop and keep quiet!
舌に乗せた 苦い感情ばかりが発火して
Only bitter feelings resting on the tongue ignite,
ダーティー ダーティー 言葉飲み込めば
dirty, dirty, if you swallow your words...
ワンツー３で砕け飛んだ
Shattered away in 1, 2, 3,
規定外で潜り乗ってんだ脳内
diving beyond regulations in my brain,
脳内 楽ならまあいっか
in my brain—if it's easy, I guess it's fine.
レディメイドの金線に 歪みかけてノイズ弾き飛んだ
Warping on ready-made gold wire, noise burst away—
後悔?後悔? やめて黙っていろ
Regrets? Regrets? Stop and keep quiet!
ワンツー３で砕け飛んだ 規定外で潜り乗ってんだ脳内
Shattered away in 1, 2, 3, diving beyond regulations in my brain!
脳内 本当だけ言って
In my brain, speaking only the truth—
レディメイドの金線に 歪みかけてノイズ弾き飛んだ
Warping on ready-made gold wire, noise burst away,
問題?問題? 遠く歌っていろ
Problem? Problem? Sing far away,
下手に乗った 苦い感情ばかりが発火して
clumsily boarding, only bitter feelings ignite!
迷い込んだ森の中 私を誘う声が
Lost deep within the forest, a voice beckons to me.
深い霧にこだまする 私の道はどっち
Echoing in the deep fog—which way is my path?
あっち そっち それとも こっち
That way, this way, or maybe over here?
優柔不断なお嬢さん
Such an indecisive young lady.
だけどそれは私も同じ あっちもそっちも歩く道
But that's the same for me—walking both this way and that way!
あー喜びや 悲しみや 愛しさまで
Ah, joy, sadness, and even affection—
いとしさまで 愛おしさまで
even preciousness—
歌にしたいもの全部 塗り重ねていったら
if we layer everything we want to turn into a song,
最初に見つけ出していたものが何分か分からなくなって
what we first sought became impossible to tell,
最後に残されたものは
and what was left at the end—
透明で得体の知れない音楽と無個性の残骸
is transparent, unfathomable music and the wreckage of individuality.
それを芸術と呼べるのか誰にも分からない
Whether that can be called art, no one knows.
誰も来ない
No one is coming.
頭の中はごちゃごちゃでも
Even if my head is all cluttered,
透明なのも悪くない
being transparent isn't so bad either.
だけど決めた 私は決めた 私の道
But I've decided, this is my own path.
あきちゃん！
Aki-chan!
あれ、ロボ子さんにはるなちゃん？
Huh, Roboco-san and Luna-chan?
あきちゃん、お誕生日！
Aki-chan, happy birthday!
おめでとう！遊ぼう！
Congratulations! Let's play!
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
お祝いしにきてくれたの？やったー！ありがとー！
You came to celebrate? Yay! Thank you!
そうだよ！今日はお誕生日ということでクイズを持ってきたのだよ！
That's right! Today is your birthday, so we brought a quiz!
そうね、私たちで考えた構成のクイズだよ！
That's right, a quiz we came up with!
え、お誕生日にクイズ？全然わかんないんだけど
Eh, a quiz for my birthday? I totally don't get it.
わかんないの、あきちゃん！お誕生日といえばクイズでしょ？
You don't get it, Aki-chan? A birthday means a quiz, right?
いやいやいや全然初めて聞いたよ、そんなの
No no no, this is the first time I've ever heard of that!
まあ、とりあえず、専用ステージにジャンプなのだよ！
Well, anyway, let's jump to the special stage!
そうなのだ、行くのだよ！
That's right, let's go!
じゃあね、手をつないで！
Okay, hold hands!
行くぞ！ジャンプ！せーの、ジャンプ！
Here we go! Jump! Ready, jump!
おかしなくなった
The sweets are gone!
ハッピーバースデー！おめでとう！
Happy birthday! Congratulations!
え、パーティーどこ行ったの？アキロゼのパーティーはどこだっけ？次のパーティー会場なのかな？
Eh, where did the party go? Where's Akiroze's party? Is this the next party venue?
え、何もないんだが
Eh, there's nothing here.
それでは、アキちゃんに今回挑戦してもらうのは！
Well then, the challenge for Aki-chan this time is...
くるまきクイズです！
The Kuromaki Quiz!
え、くるまきクイズって何？アキちゃんご存じでない？
Eh, what's a Kuromaki Quiz? Aki-chan doesn't know?
いいえ、おこと！
No, not at all!
いい男ことないな。こちらはですね
That's not right. This is...
アキちゃんに、これを持ってもらいます。おい！
Aki-chan will hold this. Hey!
そして、後ろの画面に映像、画像が流れてきますので、自分でくるまきを動かして何が問題の答えなのかを当てるというゲームです！
And since video and images will play on the screen behind, it's a game where you move the black circle yourself and guess what the answer to the puzzle is!
ええ、難しそう、大丈夫かな？
Eh, sounds difficult, will I be okay?
じゃあ早速クイズ行ってみるのだよ！
Well then, let's go straight to the quiz!
第1問！問題、仲間はずれはどれ？
Question 1! Question: Which one is the odd one out?
映像どうぞ！さあ、誕生日ワードで見つけてくれ！
Here's the video! Now, find it in the birthday words!
みんな一緒考えて！お、お、飲み物？これ、もしかしてアキちゃんが大好きな、あ、お酒なの？
Everyone think together! Oh, a drink? Is this Aki-chan's favorite... ah, alcohol?
あ、難しいよ。どれだ？コーラ？難しいぞ！コーラかな？コカコーラ？
Ah, this is hard. Which one is it? Cola? This is hard! Is it cola? Coca-Cola?
ちょっと嫌われてんじゃない？（笑）いや、ちょっと、ちょっと、追ってみて、あ、あ、ちょっと嫌われてるんじゃない？
Aren't you disliked a bit? (laughs) No, wait, wait, try following it... ah, aren't you disliked a bit?
あ、でも、カンカンカンって追ってみせる。あ！あ！それも、だっ、あ、痛い痛い痛い痛い！
Ah, but, chase it with "kan kan kan". Ah! Ah! That too, da-, ah, ouch ouch ouch ouch!
見つけたー！さあ、答えをどうぞ！
Found it! Now, give us your answer!
えへへ、これはアキちゃんの大好物！
Ehehe, this is Aki-chan's favorite!
麦ジュース！
Barley juice!
正解！
Correct!
さすが！いや、簡単すぎたのだよね。簡単すぎあったな。
As expected! No, it was too easy. It was too easy.
じゃあさ、次からはそんなね、簡単じゃないから、え？
Well then, from next time it won't be that easy, eh?
どんどん難易度上がってきますからね。覚悟してくさいよ。
The difficulty will keep going up, so be prepared.
わかった！
Understood!
それでは、第2問！
And now, Question 2!
余りの文字はどれ？そこですね、繋げたら1文字の単語になるんですけど、いらないもの、余っているものが3つあります。さあ、探してください！
"Which letters are left over?" There, if you connect them, it becomes a single-word term, but there are 3 unnecessary/leftover things. Now, find them!
えー、動け動け！探せ！余るのが3つあんのは？
Eh, move move! Search! There are 3 leftovers?
お、単語がいっぱい出てきてますね。なにこれ？シ、ヒメ、タン、アン、アン？
Oh, lots of words are coming out. What's this? Shi, hime, tan, an, an?
え？アン、アン、アン？ろ、ろ、ろ、ろぽ？
Eh? An, an, an? Ro, ro, ro, ropo?
あ、ロボ！むき、たん、繋げたらどうなるの？
Ah, robo! Muki, tan, if you connect them what happens?
シス、あ、あん、あん、タン、あ、あん、タン、ぽ、あ、ぽん、タン、ロボ、ロボ、ロボ！
Shisu, ah, an, an, tan, ah, an, tan, po, ah, pon, tan, robo, robo, robo!
は、ロボ！ひめ、シス、あ、余ってるのかなんだろ？
Ha, robo! Hime, shisu, ah, I wonder what's left over?
わかるかにゃ？そう、そう、そう、そう！
Do you know, nya? That's right, that's right, that's right!
ええと、え、まずじゃあ、繋がってた単語わかった？
Um, eh, first off, did you figure out the connected words?
繋がってた単語はね、あん、ぽん、たん、シス、ぽ！
The connected words were, an, pon, tan, shisu, po!
あー！
Ahh!
正解！
Correct!
あれ？待って！待って、やった、やった、正解だ！待って、待って！やった、正解だ！え、正解なに？ぽん、とん？シス？
Huh? Wait! Wait, yay, yay, it's correct! Wait, wait! Yay, it's correct! Eh, what's correct? Pon, ton? Shisu?
ま、じゃあ一応ね、ま、使われなかった単語3つ分かったから、今の聞かなかったことにしてあげるよ、じゃあ。
Well then, just in case, well, since you figured out the 3 unused words, I'll pretend we didn't hear that now.
使われてないやつね、何があった？
The unused ones, what were they?
1つ、
One,
姫、
Hime,
姫！お！え、ロボ子！？うぉー！
Hime! Oh! Eh, Roboco!? Whoa!
むき！むき！
Buff! Buff!
せいかい！
Correct!
なんでむきなんだよ！
Why buff?!
そこはアンチだろ！
That should be anti!
むきでしょ？
It's buff, right?
でも、あきちゃんしたはずってあったんだよ本当は。
Actually, it was supposed to be Aki-chan.
あったんだ？うん。
Really? Yeah.
そう！あったんだよ！
Right! It was there!
あったかった！付けたわ。
It was warm! I attached it.
むきまして！
Peeling!
第3も行っちゃおうかな？
Shall we go for the third one too?
問題
Question:
本物はどれ？本物は？本物は？
Which is the real one? The real one?
お手々見てちょうだい。はい、どうぞ！
Look at the hands. Here you go!
なに？
What?
さあ、探すんだぞ！
Now, go find it!
どっち？どれ？
Which? Which one?
あれ？声が！
Huh? The voice!
これは何？肉ぐみ！にい！に！
What is this? Meat gummies! Two! Two!
これあひる！
This is a duck!
お、これはダック！しゅぶしゅぶ、しゅぶしゅぶ、だっく！しゅぶしゅぶ
Oh, this is a duck! Shubu-shubu, duck!
え、本物はどれでしょう？
Eh, which one is the real one?
見てくれた？全部本物じゃないの？
Did you look? Aren't they all real?
え、あきちゃん探して！え、あきちゃん本物…あれ？
Eh, Aki-chan, search! Eh, Aki-chan... Huh?
どれが本物！？分からない！
Which one is real?! I don't know!
やばい、やばい、やばい！あれ、あきちゃん入ってないじゃん！わぁ！
Oh no! Huh, Aki-chan isn't in it! Wah!
時間切れ！
Time's up!
あきちゃんさ、どれにする本物は？何になった？
Aki-chan, which will you make real? What did you become?
え、本物はスバルザダックしか作らないから、違う！
Eh, the real one only makes Subaru the Duck, so no!
じゃあ、もう一回ちょっと見てみる？
Well, shall we take another look?
ちょっと見えてなかったからね、サービスでもう一回挑戦。
Since we couldn't see it, let's try again as a service.
さあ、みんな探してください！
Now everyone, please search!
どうぞ！
Here we go!
よし、よく見て！よく…
Alright, look closely! Closely...
え、この子本物じゃないの？
Eh, isn't this girl real?
端っこから端っこまでちゃんと見て！
Look properly from edge to edge!
見て、全部、娘からスバルまで！
Look, everything, from musume to Subaru!
あー！
Ah!
こいつだけ帽子が被ってない！
Only this guy isn't wearing a hat!
そこ！よく見て！何が違う？
There! Look closely! What's different?
本物はどれ？本物？
Which is the real one? Real?
これはどっちを本物と言えばいいのか！
Which one should be called the real one!
本物！見けた！本物は！
Real! Found it! The real one is!
さあ、どれですかね？
Now, which one could it be?
あれは、本物のあひるがいた。
That was a real duck.
正解！いたわ！
Correct! It was there!
よく分かったのらね。
You figured it out well.
いや、わしはスバルザダックって言ってないからね、僕たちは。
Well, we didn't say Subaru the Duck.
そう、西洋画にこだわりすぎないことも大事！
Right, not being too obsessed with Western art is important!
さあ、じゃあ、最終問題！第4問！
Now then, final question! Question 4!
間違っているのはどれ？
Which one is wrong?
間違っているもの？さあ探してください！
The incorrect one? Now please find it!
これはちょっと自信があります、僕。自信満々で
I'm somewhat confident in this. Full of confidence,
行くぜ！
Let's go!
やっちまったピーナッツ！
Messed up peanuts!
文字が書いてある。やっちまったピーナッツ！
There's text written. Messed up peanuts!
2022年最も使っていきたいワード、第一！
The #1 word I want to use most in 2022!
さあ、今回はやっちまったか？
Now, did I mess up this time?
やっちまってる全部！やっちまってるな！
They all messed up! You messed up!
何が見える？何が違う？
What can you see? What's different?
やっちまったピーナッツ！
Messed up peanuts!
全部見つけてね！
Find all of them!
さあ、見つかるか？
Now, can you find it?
どれだ？何が違う？時間切れ！
Which one? What's different? Time's up!
おっと、分かんないもしかして？分かんない！
Oops, could it be you don't know? I don't know!
一っちまったピーナッツ？ピーナッツ…ちょっと待って！
Did it go peanuts? Peanuts... Wait a minute!
やばい、見つかってないかもしれない！ちなみに1曲目見てたかもしれない。
Oh no, maybe it hasn't been found! By the way, maybe I watched the first song.
結構みんな気づいたんじゃないかな？本当？
Quite a few people might have noticed, right? Really?
じゃあ、あともうちょっとだけね！ありがとうございます！
Well then, just a little more! Thank you!
ゴー！やっちまったピーナッツ！
Go! Messed up peanuts!
もしかしたら映ってるかもしれないしね。
Maybe it's being shown, you know.
よく見て！よ…全部やっちまってんだよな！
Look closely! Yo... They all messed up!
やっちまったピーナッツだな！
It's messed up peanuts!
やっちまってるよねみんな。
Everyone's messing up.
やっちまったピーナッツ！やっちまった！
Messed up peanuts! Messed up!
お！やっちまったポナッツ？
Oh! Messed up ponuts?
正解！
Correct!
当てたわ！ポンスてんじゃん。
You got it! It's Ponsu-ten.
大正解！
Big correct!
いや、やっぱ最後に行くにつれて難しかったかニャー？
Man, as it got towards the end, it was difficult, meow?
いや、結構難しいし、ちょっと一言言っていい？
Well, it's quite difficult, can I say a word?
ここね、ここ実はめっちゃ暑いんだよね。書き手るよ。
Here, actually it's super hot here. I'm sweating.
みんななんか涼しい顔をしてるじゃん。
You guys all have cool faces.
なんか、これさ、不公平かなと思ったから、あきろせからも出しゃっそっかな？
I thought maybe this was unfair, so should Akirose also present one?
本当、ふたりにも汗かいてもらわないとさ
Really, you two need to work up a sweat too.
今もう困っちゃうよ
We're in trouble right now.
動くとさ、トレーニングに行きたくさ
When we move... we want to go train...
ちゃんと探し回ってもらわなきゃいけないからね
So you have to search around properly, you know.
やるの？
Are we doing this?
やるんだ！知らねえぞこの流れは
We're doing it! I have no idea what's going on!
知らねえぞ、知らねえぞ。じゃあ、いけますか？
I don't know, I don't know. Well, can we do this?
アキロゼからの問題は、こちら！メッセージを読み解け！
Aki Rosenthal's question is... right here! Decode the message!
文字をいっぱい動いてほしいな。がんばって見つけてよ
We want the letters to move around a lot. Do your best to find them.
それでは、このメッセージはみんな分かるかな？
Well then, does everyone understand this message?
いくよ。よーい、スタート！
Here we go. Ready, start!
あ、分かった人？分かった人いる？
Did anyone get it? Is there anyone who got it?
はい、もう一回。もう一回いってもらいましょう
Okay, once more. Let's have them try once more.
じゃあもう一回、頑張ってもらいましょう。よーい、スタート！
Well then, let's have them try their best once more. Ready, start!
わかんねえよ！なんだこれ？なんか文字になってきたよ、ぐずみたいな
I don't get it! What is this? It's turning into letters... like 'guzu'...
えっと…しょ…アキロゼグッズ？
Umm... sho... Aki Rosenthal goods?
正解は、こちら！
The correct answer is right here!
ということで、グッズ紹介を！え、させて頂きたいと思います！
And so, onto the merchandise introduction! Um, we'd like to present them!
ロゼ証明書＆ロゼ隊ピンバッジBOX
[Title: Rose Certificate & Rose Platoon Pin Badge Box]
証明書とピンバッジ！これってもし持ってたら、ロゼ隊の証明書の証しになっちゃうってこと？
Certificate and pin badges! If you have this, does it mean you're officially certified as a member of the Rose Platoon?
そういうこと！
That's right!
ほしいほしい！あづみあきたけ先生描き下ろしなので、豪華なボックスとカードになってるので、楽しみにしててください！
I want it, I want it! It's newly illustrated by Adumi Akitake-sensei, with a gorgeous box and cards, so please look forward to it!
ジョブズぬいぐるみとロゼ隊ぬいぐるみ
[Title: Jobzu Plushie & Rose Platoon Plushie]
ぬいぐるみ？これ、おったらもう寂しくねえな夜！
A plushie? With this, you won't be lonely at night!
そういうこと！
That's right!
こちら、はなだすみれ先生にデザインしてもらいました。もうめちゃくちゃ可愛くなっているので、抱きしめて眠ってくれよ！
This was designed by Hanada Sumire-sensei. It's super cute, so cuddle it and go to sleep!
ロゼ隊アイマスク
[Title: Rose Platoon Eye Mask]
アイマスク
Eye mask
おおー すごい！
Wow, amazing!
これアイマスクって ぬいぐるみをとぎゅってして
This eye mask, if you hug the plushie tight
アイマスクしたら もしかしてそれはアキちゃんと一緒に寝てるって思ってしまうってこと？
and wear the eye mask, does it make you feel like you're sleeping with Aki-chan?
よっ あらら あら？
Hey, oh my, oh?
夜のお供の 満塁セットはいかがですか？
How about the full-base set as your companion for the night?
うわぁ、なんかちょっと眠れなくなっちゃうかもしれない。大丈夫かな？
Wow, it might make it hard to sleep a bit. Will I be okay?
大丈夫、きっとね、アイマスクが包み込んでくれるから
It's okay, I'm sure the eye mask will wrap you up.
ああー 可愛い、可愛い！ はい、さらにです、今回はボイスもあります。
Aww, cute, cute! Yes, and furthermore, there are also voices this time.
なんだって？
What was that?
すべてASMRにて撮らせていただきました。
They were all recorded in ASMR.
やばい、やばいねこと。
This is crazy, this is crazy.
もう眠れないって。ちょっとこれタイトルも頑張って考えたから
I won't be able to sleep anymore. I worked hard on the titles too,
紹介していい？
so can I introduce them?
なんですか？
What is it?
「二人きりの誕生日アフターパーティー」って思ってよ。
Think of it as "A Birthday After-Party Just for Two."
眠れなくなっちゃうってこんなの。
Something like this makes you unable to sleep!
やばい！
Oh no!
ドキドキしちゃうじゃん。ドキドキしちゃったよ。
It makes your heart race. My heart's racing!
そしてさらに、「ヤンデレASMR 愛され上手なキミとリンゴの香り」
And furthermore, "Yandere ASMR: You, Who Are Good at Being Loved, and the Scent of Apples."
何それ？エビシュー？どういうこと？
What's that? Ebi-shu? What does that mean?
いや、ちょっとこれね、最初運営さんに上げられた時 ちょっとえちすぎるんでやめてくださいって
Well, you see, when this was first proposed by management, I said, "It's a bit too lewd, please stop,"
確かに、そうだよね、そうだよね。
That's right, isn't it? Exactly.
おなかナクナクでちょっと柔らかくしたんですけども、やっぱみんなでヤンデレ好きだからね。行きたい、行きたい。
I softened it a bit because of crying out, but everyone loves yandere after all. I want to go, I want to go.
はい、頑張りました。
Yes, I did my best.
そして、「耳舐めASMR リラックスバージョン」
And, "Ear-Licking ASMR: Relax Version."
褒められたー！褒められた！
I got praised! I got praised!
みんな褒められたい欲があると思ったから、今回欲に叶えましたよ、アキロゼで。やっほーい！やったー！
I thought everyone has a desire to be praised, so I satisfied that desire this time with Aki-Rosé. Yay! Hooray!
ということで、こちらのね、フルセット
So, this full set
数量限定で直筆サイン入りのポストカードがついているので、ぜひぜひぜひぜひゲットしてください！
comes with a postcard featuring an autograph in limited quantity, so please, please, please get it!
さらにですね、このフルセットには特典ボイスとしてさっきの、褒め舐めASMRの自己肯定感爆上げで気合いを入れたい時バージョンも！
Furthermore, this full set includes a bonus voice: the aforementioned praise-licking ASMR version for when you want to boost your self-esteem through the roof and get pumped up!
おおー。すごい、レベルアップしてる！レベル上がったね！
Ohh. Amazing, it's leveled up! You leveled up!
そう、これはもう特典にしかついていないね。もう朝とかに聞いて、よし、もう今日絶対来るみたいな時に聞いていただいて
Right, this is only included as a bonus. You can listen to it in the morning and think, "Alright, today is definitely my day,"
やる気みなぎってきちゃう！
and get super motivated!
よし、ということで、行くよみんな。おっ、行くよ。ついてきて。えっ、行くの？どっち？こっち？こっち？せーの、すっすっすっすっ...
Alright, then, let's go everyone. Oh, let's go. Follow me. Huh, we're going? Which way? This way? This way? Ready, go, swish, swish, swish...
いつもの口からでまかせばっかり喋ってる
I'm always talking rubbish
イエス ノウ どちらでもないこともあるでしょう
Yes, no, sometimes it's neither of those
いつだって世界はわたしを楽しくさせて
The world is always making me happy
いつまで動かなくなる時まで遊んでね
Play with me until the time we stop moving
しゃくしゃく余裕で暮らしたい
I want to live calmly with plenty of room
約束だって守りたい
And keep my promises too
誰かを愛すことなんて本当はとても簡単だ
Falling in love with someone is actually very easy
ずいぶん遠くまで流れ流れでせつないんです
I'm drifting far away and feeling so wistful
大切な思い出さえ忘れていきそうです
I feel like I'm even going to forget precious memories
確かな君に会いたい
I want to see you for sure
百年先も傍にいたい
I want to be by your side a hundred years from now
どんなに離れ離れでもふたりをつなぐ呪文はJOY
No matter how far apart we are, the spell connecting us is JOY
死ぬまでドキドキしたいわ
I want my heart to race until I die!
死ぬまでワクワクしたいわ
I want to feel excited until I die!
私たちは...
We are...
ずっと一緒だよ
We'll always be together.
これからもそれだけで何もいらない
From now on, just that is all I need.
君と巡り巡る季節の中で 幸せになれるように
As the seasons turn around with you, wishing I can be happy.
いつ離れてもわかんない
Even if we drift apart, I wouldn't know.
約束だって破りたい
I want to break our promises.
誰かを愛すことなんて ときどきでもこんなんだ
Loving someone... even sometimes, it's like this.
確かから君に会いたい
I definitely want to see you.
百年先もそばにいたい
I want to be by your side a hundred years from now.
どんなに離れ離れでも 二人をつなぐ
No matter how far apart we are, connecting us...
死ぬまでドキドキしたいわ
I want my heart to flutter until the day I die.
「キミのヒロインは誰…？」
"Who will be your heroine, I wonder...?"
おぼえてる優しく キミの言葉にキュンとして
I still remember your gentle words that made my heart skip a beat.
上手く言えない 代わりに笑いかけてみたのよ
Unable to say it well, I tried smiling instead.
目が合った気がした それだけで鼓動ハネた
I felt like our eyes met, and just that made my heart race.
お願いい 勘違いじゃありませんように
Oh please, I hope I'm not mistaken.
そっと心の中で熱い視線送った 振り向いてって願っちゃってた
Quietly in my heart I sent a passionate gaze, hoping you would look back.
ヒロインオーディション エントリーしたらワタシ
Your heroine audition, if I entered myself...
「ねえ、選んでくれるかな…？」
"Say, would you select me...?"
マジメな性格 おはようだけで伝わるよ
You're so down-to-earth, just a "good morning" tells it all.
何気ないつぶやき もしかしてと期待してる
Casual murmurs, hoping against hope.
眩しい素敵な人ばかりで 自信もなくて
So many dazzling, wonderful people, I lack confidence.
それでも本音では 365日もっと近づきたい
Even so, deep down, I want to get closer 365 days a year.
ワタシなりのペースになるけど
At my own pace, though.
ヒロインオーディション 勇気をだしたらキミは
Your heroine audition, if I mustered up the courage...
「ねえ、答えてくれるかな…？」
"Say, would you answer me...?"
出会った瞬間ってかなりすごいミラクル
The moment we met is an incredible miracle.
このチャンスは赤い糸 ギュッと手繰り寄せて運命にしよう
Pulling this red thread close, let's make it destiny.
信じて… まっすぐ… せーので言葉にして…！
Believe... straight ahead... all together, put it into words...!
「キミのヒロインは誰…？」
"Who will be your heroine, I wonder...?"
きっとキミの心を動かしてみせるよ
I'm sure I can move your heart.
まだまだぜんぜん足らないけど
I'm still not nearly enough, but...
ヒロインオーディション 選んでそしてワタシを
Your heroine audition, pick me and...
いつかギュッとしてほしい
...hold me tight someday.
「ありがとう、ずっと大好きだよ！」
"Thank you, I love you forever!"
ヒロインオーディション 勇気をだしたらキミは
Your heroine audition, if I mustered up the courage...
「ねえ、答えてくれるかな…？」
"Say, would you answer me...?"
出会った瞬間ってかなりすごいミラクル
The moment we met is an incredible miracle.
このチャンスは赤い糸
This chance is a red thread of fate.
ギュッと手繰り寄せて運命にしよう
Pulling it close, let's make it destiny.
信じて まっすぐ 背伸びして言葉にして
Believe, stand tall, and put it into words.
きっとヒロインなら綺麗で 王子様にチヤホヤされるでしょ?
Surely if I were a heroine, I'd be pretty and pampered by princes, right?
イェイ
Yay!
きっと君の中身は動かしてみてるよ
Surely inside you, I'm trying to move you...
窓際全部足りないけど
Even though the window side isn't enough at all...
ヒロインオーディション 選んでそして私を いつかぎゅっとして欲しい
Heroine audition—choose me, and someday hold me tight, please.
ありがとうずっと大好きなの
Thank you so much, I've always loved you.
白い雪のプリンセスは 作詞・作曲：のぼる↑
The White Snow Princess Is (Music & Lyrics: Noboru↑)
鏡よ鏡よ鏡さん
Mirror, mirror, on the wall,
世界で一番可愛いのは私にしないでよ
don't make me the fairest in the world!
棘のような視線迫る 優しいた彼女が
Thorny gazes close in; the woman who acted so kind
素敵な晩餐もてなした そっと口に含むと笑み
served a wonderful dinner, and when I tasted it, she smiled.
薄れてゆく意識の中で 夢を見ている いつかの童話
Within my fading consciousness, I dream of a fairytale of old,
時が止まる
as time stands still.
お願いKISSで目を覚まして欲しいの
Please, I want you to wake me with a kiss
白い棺から 連れ出すように
so you can lead me out of my white casket.
突き刺さる憎しみは ドラマチックな事情
The stabbing hatred is a dramatic affair,
祈っても 王子様は まだ来ない
and even as I pray, the prince hasn't come yet.
鏡よ鏡よ鏡さん ネクタイ結びや 頬に挨拶するから
Mirror, mirror, on the wall, because you tie my necktie and greet my cheek,
妬みを買わせてしまった
I ended up drawing her jealousy.
7人の小人はいるけれど 助ける素振り 知らん顔ね
There are seven dwarves, but they play dumb and act like they won't help.
そっと首を捕まえ 笑み
My neck is gently seized, and she smiles.
一粒の涙さえも拭えなくて 呼吸もままならない
I can't even wipe away a single tear, unable to even breathe properly,
視界失った
losing my vision.
消えそうだから 早く駆け付けて欲しいの
I'm about to vanish, so I want you to hurry over—
訳は聞かないで 応えられない
don't ask for the reason, I can't answer.
望まない憎まれは 深い愛の二乗
The unwanted hatred is the square of deep love;
もうすぐで いなくなるのかな
will I disappear very soon?
途切れてく命の音
The sound of life is fading away,
毒リンゴを食した少女のように 眠りにつく
falling asleep like the girl who ate the poisoned apple.
お願いKISSで目を覚まして欲しいの
Please, I want you to wake me with a kiss—
胸の中の声 届きますか
does the voice inside my chest reach you?
階段を上ったら ドアを開けるだけで
If you climb the stairs, just opening the door
見つかるよ
is enough to find me.
お願いKISSで目を覚まして欲しいの
Please, I want you to wake me with a kiss
ひと粒の
so that every single tear...
涙さえも
drops down...
温えなくて 呼吸もままならない
Unable to breathe, losing control...
お願いKISSで目を覚まして欲しいの
Please, I want you to wake me with a kiss,
独りきりの
all alone,
直立した少女のように眠りにつく
falling asleep like a lonely maiden.
お願いKISSで目を覚まして欲しいの
Please, I want you to wake me with a kiss,
胸の中の声 届きますか
does the voice in my chest reach you?
階段を上って ドアを開けるだけで
Just climbing the stairs and opening the door
見つかるよ
is all it takes to find me.
お願いKISSで目を覚まして欲しいの
Please, I want you to wake me with a kiss,
白い棺から 連れ出すように
so you can lead me out of my white casket.
突き刺さる憎しみは ドラマチックな事情
The stabbing hatred is a dramatic affair,
祈っても 王子様は まだ来ない
and even as I pray, the prince hasn't come yet.
消えてしまう その前に
Before I disappear...
ララライ ララライ 誰も知らない 名も無い今を駆けていくの
Lalalai, lalalai, nobody knows, running through an unnamed present.
あの見栄消えても伸ばして
Stretching out even if that vanity fades,
ララライ ララライ 君を知りたい 声にならない臆病さを
lalalai, lalalai, wanting to know you, this wordless cowardice—
たとえ何度迎えようとも
no matter how many times I face it.
いっそその日がパチンと切れたその時 世界が崩れ出しましたみたいだ
As if that day suddenly snapped, the world seemed to begin collapsing.
目に映る景色が悲しく笑うなら 恐れず瞼を閉じてごらん
If the scenery reflected in your eyes laughs sorrowfully, try closing your eyelids without fear.
さあ皆さんこちらへどうぞ通りなさい
Now everyone, step right through here,
架空討ちなら是非どうぞ心の踊る方へさあ
if it's a fictitious fight, please go towards where your heart dances!
新奇労れ飛び乗って盛り場な世界塗りこなして
Hop on the novelty, paint over the bustling world,
ララライ ララライ 誰も知らない愛を創りたいと願うおまじない
lalalai, lalalai, a spell wishing to create an unknown love,
時を超えた魚の様まで
like a fish transcending time...
ララライ ララライ 君を知りたい何一つ見逃さぬように
lalalai, lalalai, wanting to know you, so I don't miss a single thing,
時は誰も待ってくれないの
time waits for no one.
残酷な運命が 抗えぬ宿命が
A cruel fate, an unavoidable destiny,
案外暇もなく 星を寄せ集め鳴らして
gathering and ringing the stars with hardly any time to spare—
前が見えなくたって 君を信じてみたいの
even if I can't see ahead, I want to believe in you.
さあ皆さんこちらへどうぞ通りなさい
Now everyone, step right through here,
架空討ちなら是非どうぞ心の踊る方へさあ
if it's a fictitious fight, please go towards where your heart dances!
さあ皆さんこちらへどうぞ通りなさい
Now everyone, step right through here,
架空討ちなら是非どうぞ心の踊る方へさあ
if it's a fictitious fight, please go towards where your heart dances!
空飛ぶクジラに飛び乗って探し不満な世界を捉え尽くせ
Jump onto a flying whale and capture the dissatisfied world to the full!
ララライ ララライ 誰も知らない愛を創りたいと願うおまじない
Lalalai, lalalai, a spell wishing to create an unknown love,
あの見栄消えても伸ばして
stretching out even if that vanity fades,
ララライ ララライ 君を知りたい 声にならない臆病さを
lalalai, lalalai, wanting to know you, this wordless cowardice—
たとえ何度迎えようとも
no matter how many times I face it.
夢ならば覚めないで現実なんて誰も得もないから
If it's a dream, don't wake up, because reality offers no gain for anyone.
時は誰も待ってくれないの
Time waits for no one.
お話をしよう 昔話よりももっともっと素敵な物語
Let's hear a story, a wonderful fairy tale even better than old tales.
ふと目を上げると真っ白なうさぎ
When I suddenly looked up, a pure white rabbit
大慌てで駆けてく後を追うの
was running off in a panic, and I chased after it.
チクタクチクタク急いで行かなきゃ間に合わない！
Tick-tock, tick-tock, I have to hurry or I won't make it in time!
さあ王妃様のおなりー！
Now, her Majesty the Queen arrives!
私が女王様さあ
I am the Queen! Now then—
何か文句あるの？
Do you have any complaints?
私が歌えば誰もが屈服し 全てを服従させる王
When I sing, everyone yields, a monarch making everything submit.
あなたが女王様？
You are the Queen?
私だって美しい歌声
I too have a beautiful singing voice!
負けちゃいない おんけすとら さあ始めましょう
I won't lose! Orchestra, now let's begin—
私のミュージック！
my music!
ピアノ！
Piano!
ウッドベース！
Wood bass!
ドラムス！
Drums!
ブラスセクション！
Brass section!
みんな言うことお聞き 私のために奏でなさい
Listen to what everyone says, play for my sake!
すべては私のものよ 私の女王なのだから！
Everything is mine, because I am the Queen!
ちょっと待って これはみんなで奏でる
Wait a minute, this is music played together by everyone!
お話をしよう 昔話よりもっともっと素敵な物語
Let's tell a story, a wondrous fairy tale far better than any old legend.
ふっと目を開けると真っ白いうさぎ 大慌てでかけ後を追うの
Opening my eyes, I see a pure white rabbit rushing off in a panic, and I chase after it.
チクタクチクタク急いで行かなきゃ間に合わない！
Tick-tock, tick-tock, I must hurry or I won't make it in time!
ああチクタクチクタクギクシャクするのはもう嫌だ
Ah, tick-tock, tick-tock, I'm so sick of things being so awkward.
そらチクタクチクタク時間はどんどん減っていく
Look, tick-tock, tick-tock, the time is slipping away more and more.
もう兎に角には時間がない
Anyway, there's no time left now.
ねえそんなに慌てて一体全体どうしたの？
Hey, what on earth is going on for you to be in such a rush?
どこかの誰とはいつどこかで待ち合わせ？
Are you meeting someone somewhere at some time?
そう！彼女はチクタクとっても時間にシビアだよ
That's right! She is tick-tock very strict about time.
そうなの？そうさ！だって彼女は女王様
Is that so? That's right! Because she is the Queen.
カカクシカジカチクタクどうにも時間がないから
For this and that reason, tick-tock, we have no time to spare.
話があるならまたの機会にしておく
If you have something to discuss, let's save it for another occasion.
それならひとつだけ教えて何故そんなときでも陽気におうたを詠うの？
Then tell me just one thing: why do you sing cheerfully even at a time like this?
それはミュージックランド
Because it's Musicland.
ミュージックランド？
Musicland?
そうさミュージックランド ワンダーランド！
That's right, Musicland, Wonderland!
ここがミュージックランドだからさ！
Because this is Musicland!
じゃあお先に失礼また会う日までバイバイさようなら 待ってー！
Well, excuse me, goodbye until we meet again, farewell! Wait up!
お話をしよう
Let's tell a story.
昔話よりもっともっと素敵な物語
A wondrous fairy tale far better than any old legend.
それはありふれた魔法のフィロソフィー
It is an ordinary philosophy of magic.
みんなのハートに隠されたミュージックランド
Musicland hidden within everyone's heart.
改めてアキ・ローゼンタール 2022生誕祭ありがとうございました！
Thank you once again for joining my 2022 birthday celebration, Aki Rosenthal!
今日は、アリスのね、世界を題材にやらせていただきました。早くね、紹介したいと思います。
Today, we based the performance on the world of Alice. I'd like to introduce everyone right away.
えー、ビジーラビット役の兎田ぺこらちゃん、ありがとう！ハッピーシンガー役の常闇トワちゃん、このトワピーありがとう！
Um, Usada Pekora-chan as the Busy Rabbit, thank you! Tokoyami Towa-chan as the Happy Singer, thanks Towa-pi!
クレイジーティータイム大空スバル、スバルちゃんありがとう！
Oozora Subaru for Crazy Tea Time, thank you Subaru-chan!
インジブル、インジブルキャット役の天音かなた、ことかなたん、ありがとう！
Amane Kanata, alias Kanatan, as the Invisible Cat, thank you!
そして、ハートの女王様、インプレス役の星街すいせい、ことすいちゃん！
And Hoshimachi Suisei, alias Suisei-chan, as the Queen of Hearts / Empress!
そして最後にアリス役をやらせていただきました、アキ・ローゼンタールことアキ・ローゼンタールです！
And finally, playing the role of Alice, I am Aki Rosenthal, Aki Rosenthal!
今日はこんな素敵なプレゼントを運営さんにも頑張って作ってもらいました！こうして最高のステージ、ライブできること本当にみんなのおかげです。ありがとうございます！
Today, the management worked hard to make such a wonderful present for us! Being able to put on this amazing stage and live show is truly thanks to everyone. Thank you so much!
今日はこのあとメンバー限定配信があるので、メンバーさんは忘れずに来てください！あとグッズももうゲットしたかな？
Today, we have a member-only stream afterwards, so members please don't forget to come! Also, have you gotten your merch yet?
これから絶対ゲットしてね！ということで、今年の...
Make sure to grab yours soon! With that said, this year's...
お誕生日 ちょっと待って
Oh wait, it's my birthday! Just a second!
今年の誕生日も 本当にありがとう！
Thank you so much for my birthday this year too!
おつたん バイバーイ！
Otsutan, bye-bye!
アキロゼもみんなのところに行って アフターパーティーするぞ！
Akirose is going to everyone's place for an after-party too!
みんな大スキ～♡
I love you all so much~♡